Guide to the Paul Horgan Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- 1990 Acquisitions, 19.51; (36 boxes)
  - October 1990 Acquisition, 1933-1990, undated
    - Paul Horgan's History, lecture by Howard R. Lamar, 1984 (Box 167)
    - Farewell dinner on resignation as Director of Center for Advanced Studies, 1967 January 4 (Box 167)
    - A Writer's Eye, production correspondence, proofs, and notes, 1987-1988; 7 (Box 168)
    - A Writer's Eye, color proof and other production material, 1987-1988; 2 (Box 168)
    - A Writer's Eye, color proof and other production material, 1987-1988; 2 (Box 169)
    - A Writer's Eye, exhibition catalog and drafts, 1983-1988 (Box 169)
    - A Certain Climate, original papers, designs, galley proofs, and production stages, 1988; 5 (Box 170)
    - A Certain Climate, preparatory materials, undated; 4 (Box 171)
    - Autobiography, materials, undated (Box 172)
    - Fast Company, script, 1942 (Box 172)
    - Portraits, appraisals, and essays, undated; 3 (Box 172)
    - Robert Hunt letters to Paul Horgan, 1924-1939; 3 (Box 172)
    - New versions in English of portions of the Gospel of St. Matthew, undated; 2 (Box 172)
    - Mary Garden file and a review of Stravinksy Letters, 1987, undated (Box 172)
    - Approaches to Writing, second edition, 1987 (Box 172)
    - A Writer's Eye, galley proof, undated (Box 173 (Oversize))
    - Drawings for A Writer's Eye, 1968 (Box 173 (Oversize))
    - Photographs, undated (Box 173 (Oversize))
    - Rio Grande field sketches, 1947, undated; 3 (Box 174 (Oversize))
- 1991 Acquisitions, 5.75; (11 boxes)
  - July 1991 Acquisition, 1929-1991, undated
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 199
    - Correspondence
      - B-Z, 1969-1981, undated; 18 (Box 175)
      - Unsorted, 1929-1990; 6 (Box 175)
      - Unsorted, 1935-1990; 8 (Box 176)
      - Unsorted, 1970-1972; 7 (Box 177)
    - Writings
      - SMU Magazine, 1990 (Box 177)
      - The Journals of Thorton Wilder, uncorrected proof, 1985 (Box 177)
      - Notes, undated (Box 177)
      - "Remembering Anga" by Paul Horgan, corrected typescript, undated (Box 177)
      - Periodicals, 1984-1989 (Box 177)
      - "Paul Horgan" by Robert Gish, bound typescript, undated (Box 177)
      - Early photographs of Santa Fe, undated (Box 177)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1932-1991; 16 (Box 178)
    - Correspondence and printed matter, 1932-1984; 2 (Box 178)
    - Printed matter, 1990-1991, undated; 2 (Box 178)
    - Financial Papers
      - Account books, 1975, 1978, undated; 3 (Box 178)
      - Statements, 1970 (Box 178)
      - Income tax, 1970 (Box 178)
      - Unidentified records, 1975; 2 (Box 178)
      - Statements, 1980-1983; 9 (Box 179)
    - New Mexico Quarterly, 1951 (Box 180)
    - Slides, 1968-1986; 3 (Box 180)
    - Photographs, 6 (Box 180)
    - Entries for Royal Remarks, undated (Box 180)
    - Humorous material, limericks, parodies, undated (Box 180)
    - Doctorate of literature diploma from Boston College, undated (Box 181 (Oversize))
    - Audiovisual materials
      - Paul Horgan- Jack Logffler interview, 1988; 1 (Box 221 (Restricted Fragile))
      - A Writer's Eye, New York Public Library exhibition opening, 1985; 1 audiocassette (Box 221 (Restricted Fragile))
      - Opera shellac record albums removed from binder entitled "X Special"
        - Triviata, undated; 12" record album (Box 222 (Restricted Fragile))
        - Hamlet- Hamlet's Soliloquy and Henry VI- Glouster's Soliloquy, undated; 12" record album (Box 222 (Restricted Fragile))
        - Faust: Act III, undated; 12" record album (Box 222 (Restricted Fragile))
        - Tannhauser and Lohengrin, undated; 12" record album (Box 222 (Restricted Fragile))
        - Schubert, undated; 10" record album (Box 222 (Restricted Fragile))
        - Aida, undated; 12" record album (Box 222 (Restricted Fragile))
        - Schumann, 12" record album (Box 222 (Restricted Fragile))
        - Ave Maria and Aufenthalt, undated; 12" record album (Box 222 (Restricted Fragile))
        - Die Mainacht and Der Nussbaum, undated; 12" record album (Box 222 (Restricted Fragile))
        - Morgen and Befreit, undated; 12" record album (Box 222 (Restricted Fragile))
        - Otello, undated; 12" record album (Box 222 (Restricted Fragile))
        - Bach, undated; 12" record album (Box 222 (Restricted Fragile))
      - Opera and classical recordings, undated; 14 12" record albums (Box 223 (Restricted Fragile))
      - Opera and classical recordings, undated; 15 12" record albums (Box 224 (Restricted Fragile))
      - Opera and classical recordings, undated; 15 12" record album (Box 225 (Restricted Fragile))
      - Opera and classical recordings, undated; 16 12" record albums 1 10" record album (Box 226 (Restricted Fragile))
      - Opera and classical recordings, undated; 6 12" record albums 1 10" record album (Box 227 (Restricted Fragile))
      - Opera and classical recordings, undated; 9 12" record albums (Box 228 (Restricted Fragile))
      - Opera and classical recordings, undated; 6 12" record albums (Box 229 (Restricted Fragile))
      - Opera and classical recordings, undated; 7 12" record albums (Box 230 (Restricted Fragile))
  - August 1991 Acquisition, undated
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 202
    - Photographs of family and friends, 3 (Box 182)
    - Photographs of family and friends (Box 183 (Oversize))
  - September 1991 Acquisition, circa 1951-1955
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 195
    - Sitting Bear, pen and wash drawing, circa 1951-1955 (Box 184)
    - Quanah Parker, pen and wash drawing, circa 1951-1955 (Box 184)
    - Just Bear, pen and wash drawing, circa 1951-1955 (Box 184)
  - November 1991 Acquisition, 1983-1984, undated
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 210
    - Clerihews in a tin, 1983-1984, undated (Box 185)
- 1992 Acquisitions, 0.21; (1 box)
  - April 1992 Acquisition, 1939
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 222
    - Washington Monument: manuscript book with 18 pencil and ink sketches, inscribed to Harriet Hamilton and signed by Paul Horgan, 1939; 2 (Box 186)
  - June 1992 Acquisition, undated
    Former call number: Uncat ZA File 281
    - 11 pencil drawings, with holograph and typescript annotations, signed by Paul Horgan, undated (Box 186)
- 1993 Acquisitions, 3.71; (6 boxes)
  - August 1993 Acquisition, 1924-1993, undated
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 296
    - Correspondence
      - Letters of Rosemary Horgan Grant to Paul Horgan, xerox copies, 1986 (Box 187)
      - Correspondence, 1930-1991; 41 (Box 187)
      - Correspondence, 1991-1993, undated; 12 (Box 188)
      - Everything to Live for, correspondence and clippings, 1968-1969 (Box 188)
    - Artwork, undated (Box 188)
    - Book Reviews, circa 1955-1982; 3 (Box 188)
    - Photographs, 1939-1991, undated; 2 (Box 188)
    - Personal papers, 1924-1991; 2 (Box 188)
    - Writings
      - New Mexico, undated (Box 188)
      - What is the Question?, 1964 June 8 (Box 188)
      - The Devil's Trill, undated (Box 188)
      - Charge to the graduating class of Wesleyan University, 1963 (Box 188)
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1964-1992, undated; 4
      - Notes (Box 188)
    - Clippings, 1966-1993, undated (Box 189)
    - Printed material, 1942-1991, undated; 5 (Box 189)
    - Papers relating to teaching at Wesleyan, undated (Box 189)
    - Diploma for doctorate from D'Youville College, undated (Box 189)
    - Photograph of Hugh M. Milton, 1953 December 2 (Box 190 (Oversize))
    - Proclamation from the Mayor of Middletown establishing August 14, 1993 as Paul Horgan Day (Box 190 (Oversize))
  - October 1993 Acquisition, 1947-1963, undated
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 304
    - Transparencies #1-49, 1947-1951, undated; 45 (Box 191)
    - Unnumbered transparencies, 1947-1963, undated; 9 (Box 191)
- December 1994 Acquisition, 0.21; (1 box)
  Pencil sketches, ink drawings, watercolor drawings and printed material by Paul Horgan, including "Scribble," "Unpublished Poet," and [Rio Grande].
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 428
  - Artwork, circa 1949-1987, undated
    - Scribble, undated (Box 192)
    - Coach, undated (Box 192)
    - Archdeacon McLapin, undated (Box 192)
    - Sheet Metal Sculptor, undated (Box 192)
    - Personnel, undated (Box 192)
    - Unpublished Poet, undated (Box 192)
    - Miss Trotter, of the Third Grade Home Room (No one ever thinks she may have a home, undated (Box 192)
    - ABC Midday News Brief, undated (Box 192)
    - Never the same since seeing Mr. Chips, undated (Box 192)
    - Can Still Do Character Roles, anyway..., undated (Box 192)
    - To Whom Madison Avenue Listens, God help us., undated (Box 192)
    - Notre Dame, '58, 1958 (Box 192)
    - Survivor of Pre-Orthodentisty, undated (Box 192)
    - Mille Tatiana Borevitvch poet (untranslated), undated (Box 192)
    - Dean Van Cleff, of the Music Faculty, undated (Box 192)
    - Stock Company, undated (Box 192)
    - Mme Zwieback, singer, once known as The Toast of Vienna, undated (Box 192)
    - Felicia Wrenn, of the Louisville Opera Co., undated (Box 192)
    - Hermeneutics, undated (Box 192)
    - Citizens of the Phone Pad, 1989, undated; 13 drawings (Box 192)
    - Character Woman, undated (Box 192)
    - Phone doodles (5 drawings), circa 1989 (Box 192)
    - Concert Afflatus, undated (Box 192)
    - Parody and Paradox in Marx, undated (Box 192)
    - The Art of Banking, undated (Box 192)
    - Psychoeconomics, undated (Box 192)
    - Croquet, undated (Box 192)
    - Psychoevangelism, undated (Box 192)
    - Postextensialism, undated (Box 192)
    - The Firm, 1980; 14 drawings (Box 192)
    - Remedial Reading, undated (Box 192)
    - Diocesan Fiscal Director, undated (Box 192)
    - Sir Thomas Beecham Washington-National Symphony, circa 1951 (Box 192)
    - Toscanini (8"x5"), undated (Box 192)
    - [Rio Grande], watercolor, circa 1950 (Box 192)
    - Phone Doodles, circa 1986; 12 drawings (Box 192)
    - Le Roughneck, circa 1989 (Box 192)
    - This is a sample of Paul Horgan's left-hand writing On verso: This is a sample of my handwriting for Paul Horgan, undated (Box 192)
    - New School of Social Research, Department of Music, undated (Box 192)
    - Henry James opting for London, undated (Box 192)
    - Colette, undated (Box 192)
    - On the Painting of Samuel Green, article by Paul Horgan, printed version, circa 1970 (Box 192)
    - Romeo and Juliet VIII opening, with printer's reduction notes, circa 1949 (Box 192)
    - Pitcher, circa 1987 (Box 192)
    - Ukraine, undated (Box 192)
    - Berlin, undated (Box 192)
    - USSR, undated (Box 192)
    - Middle West Side, undated (Box 192)
    - Dallas, undated (Box 192)
    - Sweden, undated (Box 192)
    - U.K., undated (Box 192)
    - Lithuania, undated (Box 192)
    - France, undated (Box 192)
    - Oxon (watercolor), 1968 (Box 192)
    - Stand-Up Comic, undated (Box 192)
    - All for Hockey-Distaff, undated (Box 192)
- 1995 Acquisitions, 12.71; (15 boxes)
  - November 1995 Acquisition, 1939-1994
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 462
    - Nelly Bruce, undated; 3 (Box 221 (Restricted Fragile))
    - Unsorted correspondence, undated; 2 (Box 193)
    - Clippings and correspondence relating to Edmund Wilson, undated (Box 193)
    - Of America East & West: Selections from the Writings of Paul Horgan, printed proof, 1984; 4 (Box 193)
    - A Distant Trumpet, undated; 4 (Box 193)
    - Writings of Joseph Reed, undated (Box 193)
    - Clippings and correspondence, 1968-1985; 2 (Box 193)
    - Writings of Daniel Patrick Moynihan, 1961-1989; 3 (Box 193)
    - Bookend, undated (Box 193)
    - Paul Horgan's field study drawings for Lamy of Santa Fe, undated (Box 193)
    - Tracings: A Book of Partial Portraits, undated; 2 (Box 193)
    - Tracings: A Book of Partial Portraits, undated; 3 (Box 194)
    - Chapter I from an unfinished novel, undate (Box 194)
    - The Paterson Tales, general prologue, undated (Box 194)
    - Fast Company, script, 1977 (Box 194)
    - Striking public photographs, clippings, undated (Box 194)
    - Photographs, correspondence, and passports, undated (Box 194)
    - Parodies, undated (Box 194)
    - Unwritten chapters, xerox copies, undated (Box 194)
    - Correspondence and fiscal reports, 1990-1995 (Box 194)
    - Correspondence, notes, date book, 1979-1994 (Box 194)
    - Drawings, postcards, and correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 194)
    - Correspondence and writings, 1991-1994 (Box 194)
    - Datebook, 1963 (Box 194)
    - Jere Knight, correspondence and poetry, 1993-1994 (Box 194)
    - Travel documents, 1953 (Box 194)
    - Datebook and writings, xerox copies, 1945-1955 (Box 194)
    - Correspondence
      - S, 1974-1981 (Box 194)
      - S.M.U., undated (Box 194)
      - Stravinsky, undated (Box 194)
      - Texas Monthly Press and Gulf Publishing, 1983-1990 (Box 194)
      - Timbuktu, undated (Box 194)
      - Wesleyan, 1989-1990 (Box 194)
      - Y, undated (Box 194)
      - Mrs. Foster E. Zaiser, 1980-1984 (Box 195)
    - The Dean of Santa Fe, marginal sketches, udated, 1991 (Box 195)
    - Death, Mr. President, undated (Box 195)
    - Writings, undated (Box 195)
    - Dean of Santa Fe, undated (Box 195)
    - Notes, undated (Box 195)
    - The Young King of Egypt by Paul Horgan, undated (Box 195)
    - Properties, notes, undated (Box 195)
    - Typescript of "jollification", 1965-1976 (Box 195)
    - Files relating to the Aspen Award, 1968-1991 (Box 195)
    - Notes, undated (Box 195)
    - A Word of Thanks and Appreciation from Paul Horgan, undated (Box 195)
    - El Dorado and Return, undated (Box 195)
    - Harper's Monthly Magazine, xerox copies, undated (Box 195)
    - Transcript of interview regarding J. Robert [Coppenheimer?] (Box 195)
    - Articles by Paul Horgan, undated (Box 195)
    - Unwritten chapters, undated (Box 195)
    - Interview with Robert Gish, 1994 (Box 195)
    - Pets, memoir, undated (Box 195)
    - Forward to Great River, undated (Box 195)
    - Projects, undated (Box 195)
    - Articles by Paul Horgan, undated (Box 195)
    - Drawings, undated (Box 195)
    - El Dorado and Return, typescript, undated (Box 195)
    - Notes and photographs, undated (Box 195)
    - Death, Mr. President, xerox typescript, undated (Box 195)
    - Notes, undated; 2 (Box 196)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 196)
    - Correspondence, 1991, undated (Box 196)
    - Portrait sketches, undated (Box 196)
    - Lamy of Santa Fe, notes and reviews, undated (Box 196)
    - Printed material and correspondence, 1992-1994; 2 (Box 196)
    - Comic drawings, undated (Box 196)
    - Correspondence and notes, undated (Box 196)
    - Moments, notes, undated; 2 (Box 196)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1994; 2 (Box 196)
    - Literary Revision: The Inexact Science of Getting it Right, by Joseph W. Reed, 1990 (Box 196)
    - Correspondence, clippings, and Festschrift for Paul Horgan, undated (Box 196)
    - Notes and Deaths of the Poets by Joseph and Kit Reed, 1991, undated (Box 196)
    - Printed material and correspondence, 1991-1993, undated; 2 (Box 196)
    - Correspondence A-J, 1984-1994, undated; 10 (Box 197)
    - K-R, 1984-1994, undated; 2 (Box 198)
    - Printed material, writings, and correspondence, undated; 13 (Box 198)
    - The People, script, undated (Box 198)
    - Imaginary Dialogues, by Ernest Bacon, 1989 (Box 198)
    - Paul Horgan bookplates, undated (Box 198)
    - No Quarter Given, corrected copy, undated (Box 199)
    - Printed material, writings, and correspondence, 1963-1994, undated; 5 (Box 199)
    - JA Notebook, undated (Box 199)
    - Getting it Together by Steven Schwartz, undated (Box 199)
    - The Blue Boat on St. Anne by F.D. Reeve, undated (Box 199)
    - Candy Pie by Joseph W. Reed, undated (Box 199)
    - The Clerihews of Paul Horgan, undated (Box 199)
    - Tracings, clippings and reviews, 1994 (Box 199)
    - Printed material, writings, and correspondence, undated (Box 199)
    - War Department correspondence, undated (Box 199)
    - Whitewater, correspondence with University of Texas Press, 1986 (Box 199)
    - Dictionary of Literary Biography Yearbook, correspondence, 1986 (Box 199)
    - Photoduplicaiton order for Some People from No Quarter Given, 1994 (Box 199)
    - Short stories, undated; 3 (Box 199)
    - Forty-Four Brass Buttons, undated (Box 199)
    - The Cyclopeida of American Biography, 1939 (Box 199)
    - Whitewater, contract, 1986-1987 (Box 199)
    - Drawings, undated (Box 199)
    - Short Stories, undated (Box 200)
    - Typesetting for Josiah Gregg and His Vision of the Early West, undated (Box 200)
    - Death Mr. President, script, undated; 2 (Box 200)
    - Printed material, writings, and correspondence, undated; 2 (Box 200)
    - Notes and drawings, undated (Box 200)
    - Magazine articles, xerox copies, undated (Box 200)
    - Writings and notes, undated (Box 200)
    - Death Mr. President, 1989, undated; 4 (Box 200)
    - A Tree on the Plains, 1991-1994 (Box 200)
    - Correspondence and photographs, undated (Box 200)
    - Clippings, 1984-1992 (Box 200)
    - Datebooks and copies of articles, 1955,1977 (Box 200)
    - Clippings and printed material, 1956-1988 (Box 201)
    - Clippings and reviews, 1942-1943 (Box 201)
    - Datebook and correspondence, 1959-1983 (Box 201)
    - Addresses by David McCullough, 1984-1989 (Box 201)
    - National Geographic, 1982 November (Box 201)
    - Papago Christmas by Bonaventure Nite, 1980 (Box 201)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1983; 2 (Box 201)
    - Printed material, 1981-1990 (Box 201)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 201)
    - Correspondence and printed material, 1991-1992 (Box 201)
    - Writings and notes, undated (Box 201)
    - D.P.M.- chapters to read, undated (Box 201)
    - Correspondence, notes, and clippings, 1972-1980, undated; 4 (Box 201)
    - Drawings, undated (Box 201)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 201)
    - Dust and Lilacs, drafts, 1990, undated; 3 (Box 201)
    - Flora Langermann Spiegelberg: Grand Lady of Santa Fe by Michael L. Lawson, 1975 (Box 202)
    - Short stories, photocopies, undated; 2 (Box 202)
    - Alternative design for the library of Strawberry Hill, with Richar Bentley's notes, print, 1988 (Box 202)
    - Datebook, photocopy, 1944 (Box 202)
    - A Writer's Eye, expenses, 1984 (Box 202)
    - Financial papers, undated; 2 (Box 202)
    - Approaches to Writings, dust jackets, undated (Box 202)
    - Cecil Spencer by Maurice Baring and engravings by Paul Horgan, 1929, undated (Box 202)
    - The New Criterion, 1992 October (Box 202)
    - Art & Antiques, correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 202)
    - Stanley Marcus, correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 202)
    - By Firelight, original full text, undated (Box 202)
    - Lecture on Maurice Baring by Frank Hills and drawings, 1971, undated (Box 202)
    - Maurice Barring works, 1924-1956 (Box 202)
    - Datebook, photocopy, 1945 (Box 202)
    - Maurice Baring Reconsidered, undated (Box 202)
    - No Quarter Given, photocopy, undated (Box 202)
    - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 202)
    - American Poetry Review, 1993 (Box 202)
    - The American Scholar, 1993 (Box 202)
    - Printed material, 1960, 1993 (Box 202)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1993; 2 (Box 202)
    - War Choices, 1991 (Box 202)
    - Poems, Good Friday, 1941 (Box Record Album storage)
    - Photographs, undated; 2 (Box 202)
    - Newspaper articles, photocopies, undated (Box 203)
    - A Distant Trumpet, notices, 1960 (Box 203)
    - Narrow Escapes in the Pentagon, undated (Box 203)
    - Paul Horgan: A Biographical Note, undated (Box 203)
    - Clippings, undated; 2 (Box 203)
    - Reviews, 1991-1992 (Box 203)
    - Not Even a Footnote, undated (Box 203)
    - Short Stories, undated; 4 (Box 203)
    - Printed material, 1972-1984 (Box 203)
    - Good Friday, poetry, 1968-1969 (Box 203)
    - Who's Who in America, biographical information, 1994 (Box 203)
    - To Every Goliath, photocopy, undate (Box 203)
    - The Young Robert Oppenheimer in Summer, undated (Box 203)
    - Good Friday, undated (Box 203)
    - Sir Thomas Beecham, portrait [removed from frame], undated (Box 203)
    - Oxford Types [removed from frame], 1995 June 10 (Box 203)
    - Chartres- Old House & Telephone Wires [removed from frame], 1955 June 20 (Box 203)
    - Southampton Water, watercolor by Paul Horgan [removed from frame], 1972 (Box 203)
    - Undergraduates Oxford [removed from frame], 1955 June 10 (Box 203)
    - Bow- R.M.S. Queen Elizabeth [removed from frame], 1955 May 5 (Box 203)
    - Tennyson Street- Swindon [removed from frame], 1955 July 24 (Box 203)
    - Bursts of Light at Sea [removed from frame], 1955 May 6 (Box 203)
    - Glass object [paper weight], undated (Box 204)
    - Paul Horgan Reads Paul Horgan, 1976; 1 (Box 221 (Restricted Fragile))
    - Unidentified, undated; 1 (Box 221 (Restricted Fragile))
    - By Dark Cocytus' Shore by Edmund Wilson, signed, undated (Box 205 (Oversize))
    - Certificate of honorary fellowship in The School of American Research [removed from frame], 1977 September 19 (Box 205 (Oversize))
    - Reviews, 1954-1991 (Box 205 (Oversize))
    - A Writer's Eye, exhibit posters, 1985 (Box 205 (Oversize))
  - November 1995 Acquisition, 1952-1991
    Former call number Uncat ZA MS 578
    - Southwest Review, 1974 (Box 206)
    - Saintmaker's Christmas Even, unbound sheets, 1986 (Box 206)
    - Ecclesia, 1952 (Box 206)
    - A Writer's Margin by Paul Horgan, reprinted from The Yale Review, 1987 (Box 206)
    - L'Apres-midi de Mary Garden by Paul Horgan, reprinted from The Yale Review, 1987 (Box 206)
    - The Thin Mountain Air, printed, edited for revision, undated (Box 206)
    - Everything to Live For, printed, edited for revision, undated (Box 206)
    - The American Scholar, 1990 (Box 206)
    - The Yale Review, 1989, 1987; 3 (Box 206)
    - Festival in honor of Igor Stravinsky, 1962 (Box 206)
    - The American Scholar, 1991 (Box 206)
    - A Tree on the Plains, undated; 2 (Box 206)
    - Manuscript material removed printed items, 1973, undated; 22 (Box 206)
  - November 1995 Acquisition, undated
    Former call number Uncat MSS 59
    - Manuscript material removed from printed items, undated; 41 (Box 207)
- May 1996 Acquisition, 1962; (1 folder)
  Former call number Uncat ZA File 365
  - New Mexico Valley: watercolor, published in The Writers Eye, 1962 (Box 208)
- December 1998 Acquisition, 1972; (1 folder)
  Former call number Uncat ZA File 394
  - 12 pencil portrait drawings, 1 typed letter signed, and 1 autograph note signed to Louise Rosenbaum, 1972 January (Box 208)
- March 1999 Acquisition, 1942-1976; 5.75; (8 boxes)
  Former call number Uncat ZA MS 609
  - Great River, research notes, undated; 10 (Box 208)
  - Short story and novel typescripts, undated; 10 (Box 209)
  - Lamy of Santa Fe, typed leaves, undated (Box 209)
  - Lamy of Santa Fe, printed and xeroxed background material, undated (Box 209)
  - Contracts and agreements, 1951-1969 (Box 209)
  - Biographical materials, 1961-1976; 4 (Box 210)
  - Speaking engagements, 1961-1965 (Box 210)
  - Biographical resume, undated (Box 210)
  - Television, 1963-1964 (Box 210)
  - Writing and reviews, 1964-1965 (Box 210)
  - Things as They Are, 1964-1966 (Box 210)
  - Memories of the Future, 1966 (Box 210)
  - The Common Heart, 1966 (Box 210)
  - Monograph on Peter Hurd, 1965-1966 (Box 210)
  - Financial papers, 19621965 (Box 210)
  - Unsorted outgoing correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 210)
  - The Wesleyan University Alumnus, 1963 May (Box 210)
  - Western trip, 1965 (Box 210)
  - New Mexico State University Bulletin, 1964 (Box 210)
  - Great River, notecards, undated; 2 (Box 210)
  - Great River, notecards, undated; 9 (Box 211)
  - First sketches OCS, 1942 (Box 212)
  - A Time for Battle, undated (Box 212)
  - Unidentified short story, undated (Box 212)
  - One Red Rose for Christmas, undated (Box 212)
  - A Prayer for Rain, undated (Box 212)
  - The Rio Grande: River of Paradox, undated (Box 212)